Guide to the Papers Relating to Blind Date and New Blind Date
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Papers relating to Blind Date and New Blind Date
1979-2005
1987-1998
YCAL MSS 225
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.09
(5 boxes)
Collection consists of production files, audio recordings, and printed and other materials relating to the literary magazines Blind Date and New Blind Date. The production files contain submissions of short fiction, poetry, interviews, and reviews, many from San Francisco area writers, including instructors and students at the New College of California poetics program. Contributors include: Tom Clark, Diane Di Prima, Edward Dorn, Jack Foley, Gloria Frym, Dick Gallup, Amy Gerstler, Jack Hirschman, Anselm Hollo, Bill Knott, Richard Kostelanetz, Jonathan Lethem, David Meltzer, Eileen Myles, Alice Notley, Andrew Schelling, and others. In additon to the production files, there are several audio recordings of interviews with Bay Area writers and artists, including Jim Carroll, Howard Hart, and William Talcott, as well as the vendor's item-level description of the archive.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Granary Books, Inc. on the Alfred Z. Baker, Jr. Fund, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile materials in Box 5 may only be consulted with permission of the appropriate curator.
Blind Date (1987-1991) and New Blind Date (1997-1998)
Blind Date (1987-1991), a literary magazine edited in Berkeley, California by novelist and poet Owen Hill, published short fiction, poetry, and interviews. New Blind Date (1997-1998), also edited by Hill, ran as a limited edition newsletter focused on the contemporary poetry scene, with reviews, gossip, short fiction, and poetry.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of production files, audio recordings, and printed and other materials relating to the literary magazines Blind Date and New Blind Date. The production files contain submissions of short fiction, poetry, interviews, and reviews, many from San Francisco area writers, including instructors and students at the New College of California poetics program. Contributors include: Tom Clark, Diane Di Prima, Edward Dorn, Jack Foley, Gloria Frym, Dick Gallup, Amy Gerstler, Jack Hirschman, Anselm Hollo, Bill Knott, Richard Kostelanetz, Jonathan Lethem, David Meltzer, Eileen Myles, Alice Notley, Andrew Schelling, and others. In additon to the production files, there are several audio recordings of interviews with Bay Area writers and artisits, including Jim Carroll, Howard Hart, and William Talcott, as well as the vendor's item-level description of the archive.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Production Files, 1979-1998. II. Other Materials, 1987-2005.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Poetry, Modern -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials; Sound recordings; Authors; Poets; Carroll, Jim, active 1987; Clark, Tom, 1941-; Di Prima, Diane, 1934-; Dorn, Edward, 1929-1999; Foley, Jack, 1940-; Frym, Gloria; Gallup, Dick, 1941-; Gerstler, Amy; Hart, Howard, 1927-; Hill, Owen, 1955-; Hirschman, Jack, 1933-; Hollo, Anselm, 1934-2013; Knott, Bill, 1940-2014; Kostelanetz, Richard, 1940-; Lethem, Jonathan, 1964-; Meltzer, David, 1937-2016; Myles, Eileen, 1949-; Notley, Alice, 1945-; Schelling, Andrew, 1953-; Talcott, William, 1936-; New College of California
- Production Files, 1979-1998; Series I; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I. Production Files is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains files for contibutors to both Blind Date and New Blind Date magazines, consisting chiefly of submissions of poetry, short fiction, and reviews. There are holograph and typescript drafts, photocopies, and computer printouts of word processing and e-mail files. Some files contain correspondence to magazine editor Owen Hill.
  - Albert, Gwendolyn, 1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anderson, Hal, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anger, Chris, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arbogast, Johnny, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Berkson, Bill, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Berlin, Lucia, 1997 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Black, Noel, 1997-1998, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bolden, Joseph, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bonnell-Kangas, Nancy, 1987-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brenner, Summer, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brook, James, 1988-1998, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Browne, J., undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chang, Lisa, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cherkovski, Neeli, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - [Clark, Juliet], undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clark, Tom, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Collom, Jack, 1996-1998, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Davis, Ray, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dawson, Fielding, 1987-1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Dean, Stephanie, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Devaney, Tom, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Di Prima, Diane, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dorn, Edward, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - [Dovetonsils, Anselm?], undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - [Dovetonsils, Don?], undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Ducey, Dylan Brie, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Fansworth, Vincent, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Foley, Jack, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Frym, Gloria, 1989-1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Gallup, Dick, [1987?] April 28 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Gerstler, Amy, 1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Gomez, Max, 1997 September 4 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Hansen, Michele, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Hart, Howard, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Hechtman, Eugene, 1980-1981, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Henning, Barbara, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Herman-Giddens, Melantha, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Hill, Owen, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Hirschman, Jack, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Hollo, Anselm, 1987 January 27 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Hydock, J., undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Jama, Stephern, 1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Jameson, Carol, 1986-1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Kennelly, Laura, 1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Knott, Bill, 1998 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Kostelanetz, Richard, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Lasker-Schüler, Else, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Leigh, Julianne, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Lethem, Jonathan, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Lethem, [Maria?], undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Includes photographs
  - Leto, Denise, 1997-1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Lowell, Jim, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - McBride, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Macdonald, Elizabeth, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - McNaughton, Duncan, 1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Mariah, Paul, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Meltzer, David, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Menefee, Sarah, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Miller, Errol, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Moore, Abd al-Hayy, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Morris, Michael, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Mueller, Jack, 1987 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Murphy, Jay, 1998 January 8 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Mycue, Edward, 1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Myles, Eileen, 1997 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Nach, Michael, undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Nelson, Pat, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Nettelbeck, F. A., 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Nichols, Robert S., 1988 July (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Nordlund, James, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Notley, Alice, 1998 March 7 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Opstedal, Kevin, 1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Paradiz, Valerie, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Patenaude, Bob, undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Peters, Robert, 1998, undated (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Pettet, Simon, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Phipps, Wanda, 1987 March 11 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Rood, Aliza, 1998 June (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Porges, M. F., undated (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Price, Michael, undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Retecki, Richard, undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Richards, Brian, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Riley, Karen, 1986-1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Robertson, R. D., 1987 October 4 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Robinson, Ann, 1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Ronan, Stephen, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Rose, Judith, undated (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Sanzgiri, Jyostsna, 1987 October 5 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Schaffer, Barbara Joan, 1998 April 16 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Schelling, Andrew, 1998 January 31 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Sherman, Amy Elliott, 1986-1999, undated (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Silberg, Richard, undated (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Smith, Dale, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Smith, Fred, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Spade, Amy, undated (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Svoboda, Alva, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Talcott, William, 1987-1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Topp, Mike, 1998 December (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Tritten, Larry, undated (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Valaorites, Nanos, 1979-1985, undated (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Vinograd, Julia, 1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Walden, T., undated (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Wainio, Ken, 1998, undated (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Wentworth, David, 1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Williams, Jeanie C., undated (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Witte, Pamela, 1988 October 17 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Wright, M., undated (Box 3, Folder 107)
- Series II. Other Materials, 1987-2005; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series II. Other Materials is organized into three subseries: Audio Recordings of Interviews, Printed Material, and Other.
  The three subseries include audio cassette recordings of interviews with writers, printed copies of issues of Blind Date and New Blind Date, as well as covers and corrected proofs, and other material.
  - Audio Recordings of Interviews
    - Carroll, Jim, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Clark, Tom, [1987] (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Frym, Gloria, [1989] (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Hart, Howard, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Talcott, William, undated (Box 4, Folder 112-113)
  - Printed Material
    - First Blind Date, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 114-115)
    - New Blind Date, 1997 November (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - New Blind Date #2, 1997 December (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - New Blind Date #3, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - New Blind Date #6, undated (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Covers, 1987-1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Proofs, [1987-1998] (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Other
    - Biographical statement, undated (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Mailing lists and labels, undated (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Subscription letters and financial records, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Vendor 's description of archive, [2005?] (Box 4, Folder 125)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.42; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Audiocassettes (In Series II), 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 126-131)
    Box 5 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Jim Carroll interview, 1987 June 27; 1; 00:54:13; There is static on the tape. The program begins and ends abruptly. (Box 5, Item barcode 39002091399379)
    - Tom Clark, [1987]; 1; 01:35:08; There is high background noise on the tape. The program ends abruptly. (Box 5, Item barcode 39002091399387)
    - Gloria Frym interview, [1989]; 1; 01:34:53; The program begins and ends abruptly. There is static and high background noise on the tape. (Box 5, Item barcode 39002091399395)
    - Howard Hart interview, 1990; 1; 01:26:16; The program begins and ends abruptly. There is static and high background noise on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 5, Item barcode 39002091399403)
    - William Talcott, undated; 1; 01:34:44; There is high background noise on the tape. The right channel recorded at a lower volume on the recording. The program ends abruptly. (Box 5, Item barcode 39002091399411)
    - William Talcott 3, undated; 1; 00:54:01; The program begins abruptly. The recording drops out at the beginning of the tape. There is static on the recording. The right channel was recorded at a lower volume on the tape. There is high background noise on the audio. (Box 5, Item barcode 39002091399429)